Hello English learners,
welcome to another great lesson
with English pod. My
name is Marko and I'm Erica.
So, Erica, how are you today?
I'm doing pretty well
and I think we've got
a good lesson today,
a really helpful lesson.
What are we talking about today?
We have an elementary lesson
about making an appointment.
All right, making an appointment.
Yeah, that's really
helpful, I guess you have
to make appointments
for the doctor or at work.
At work, or with
your friends, yeah.
So, this is language that you can
use every day to make appointments.
Great, well, so why don't we take
a look at our vocabulary preview?
Very vocabulary preview.
We only have one word today
which you need to know to
understand this dialogue
and it is financial advisor.
Financial advisor.
So, what is a financial advisor?
A financial advisor
is a person who gives
suggestions or recommendations
about investing money.
Someone who wants you to
put money in the stock markets.
Okay, great.
I guess we're ready now to listen
to our dialogue for the first time.
And as always, it's going
to be at a normal speed,
but you don't have to
worry about it because
we'll come back and teach
you all the important words.
Hello?
Favorite consulting? How may I help you?
Yes, this is Julian
Horton, and I'm calling
to the range in appointment
with Ms. McNady.
Certainly, what day were you thinking of?
How's bed day?
Does she have any time available then?
Um, let me double check.
Unfortunately, she's
booked solid on Thursday.
How does next
Monday work for you?
Actually, I've got something scheduled
on Monday. Can't you do a Tuesday?
Sure, Tuesday's perfect.
May I ask where you're calling from?
Sure, let's find out your advisors.
Oh, actually, Tuesday's no good.
Sorry about that.
Well, I guess Ms. McNeely does not
want to speak to any financial advisors.
Yeah, I guess she doesn't really
want to invest in the stock market, huh?
Or maybe she just gets too
many phone calls from them.
Yeah, yeah. If you have money, I guess
you'll get phone calls from people like that.
I guess we don't have that problem, okay?
No, we don't.
Okay, let's start with our
language takeaway for today.
Language takeaway.
So, forwards today,
the first one is available.
Available. Available. Available. Available.
Available. Meaning that you are not busy.
But you're free. You're free.
You're not busy.
Exactly. Let's move to our next word.
Double check.
Double check. Double check. Double check.
Double check. I think we've
got some examples of this phrase.
Example one.
Do you have the tickets?
I think so, but let me just double check.
Example two.
I thought I sent that email
already, but let me double check.
Okay, so double check basically
means to check something twice.
Exactly. To check it again.
Okay, our third word for
language takeaway today
is scheduled scheduled
scheduled scheduled.
S-C-H-E-D-U-L-E-D scheduled scheduled.
So, when you have something scheduled,
it means that you have something planned.
Yeah, or booked at that
time, booked at that time.
Yeah, we've got a lunch
schedule this afternoon, don't we?
Yes, we do. All right. Great lunch.
Looking forward to it.
And our last word for
today is booked solid.
Booked solid. Booked solid.
B-O-O-K-E-D. Booked solid.
So, we have some great examples
on how you can use this great
phrase booked solid, and you
can understand what it means.
Example one.
I can't get a hotel room.
They're booked solid
until after the new year.
Example two.
I'm sorry, there are no seats
available on these flights.
We booked solids over
the Christmas holidays.
Example three.
Sorry, I can't meet with you today.
I'm booked solid.
Okay, great. So, book solid basically is.
You have no free time, no available time.
Right.
So, you've got appointments
scheduled all day.
All day, great.
So, with this in mind, now we can
listen to our dialogue a second time.
This time, it's going to be slow so
we can understand a little bit better.
Hello, fair brick consulting.
How may I help you?
Yes, this is Julianne
Horton, and I'm calling
to arrange an appointment
with Ms. McNeely.
Certainly, what date were you thinking of?
How's Thursday?
Does she have any time available then?
Um, let me double-check.
No. Unfortunately, she's
booked solid on Thursday.
How does next Monday work for you?
Actually, I've got something
scheduled on Monday.
Can she do Tuesday?
Sure.
Tuesday's perfect.
May I ask where you're calling from?
Sure.
Merton Financial Advisors.
Oh.
Actually, Tuesday's no good.
Sorry about that.
Okay, so now it's a
little bit more clear, and
with this, we can start
with putting it together.
Putting it together.
There's some great examples
in this dialogue of phrases
you can use when you need
to schedule an appointment.
And we're going to look at those today.
In the dialogue, we
heard Julianne ask about
making an appointment,
and she said this.
I'm calling to arrange an
appointment with Ms. McNeely.
So this is a great way to
schedule an appointment
to ask for some time
from somebody else.
Yeah, and we have some
more examples of this phrase.
Example one.
Please book an appointment for next week.
Example two.
Please schedule an
appointment for next week.
Great.
So after that, when you're
scheduling an appointment, you
need to suggest a day when
maybe that person has time.
Yes.
Let's listen to what
they said in the dialogue.
How's birthday?
Does she have any time available then?
You say, "Well, how's
Thursday or how's Tuesday?"
And maybe that person
doesn't have time that
day, so they'll say
something like this.
Fancy dinner Tuesday.
Okay, Erica.
So if I want to have a meeting with
you, I would say, "How's Monday sound?
" Or "How's Monday?"
Monday's no good.
I'm busy all day.
How's Tuesday?
Sorry.
Tuesday's no good either.
What about Wednesday?
Okay.
Wednesday works.
All right.
Great.
Wednesday's perfect.
Okay.
It's great.
So we have a meeting on Wednesday.
Okay.
Yeah.
Those are some great phrases.
Hey, for scheduling an appointment.
Yeah.
They're really good.
Okay.
So now we can listen
to our dialogue a third
time and we're ready to understand
everything that we've just talked about.
Hello.
Favorite consulting?
How may I help you?
Yes.
This is Julianne Horton.
And I'm calling to the range in an
appointment with an incident meeting.
Certainly.
What day were you thinking of?
How's Wednesday?
Does she have any time available then?
Um, let me double check.
Unfortunately, she's
booked solid on Thursday.
How does next Monday work for you?
Actually, I've booked
something scheduled on Monday.
Can't she do a Tuesday?
Sure.
Tuesday's perfect.
May I ask where you're calling from?
Sure.
Let's find out your advice.
Oh.
Actually, Tuesday's no good.
Sorry about that.
The language in this dialogue
is really useful, isn't it, Marco?
Yeah.
It's from an everyday situation.
You always have to make
appointments at some point.
Yes.
I think we said earlier,
it's language you
can use when you need to talk
about work with your boss, maybe?
Right.
Or when you need to
do daily things, like go
to the doctor, or even when you're
planning something with your friends.
Right.
Yeah.
You can use this in all those situations.
And all those situations.
Uh-huh.
Great.
Well, we're at a time now, but I hope
you enjoyed our lesson and found it useful.
And if you have any questions or comments,
please go to our website at EnglishPod.
com where we'll be
there to answer everything.
Yes.
We will.
Thanks for coming, guys.
And until next time.
Bye.
[MUSIC PLAYING]